<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[dm's blog]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[David Moreno's technical and not too technical blog]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://damog.net/blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://damog.net/blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Moreno]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2014/08/08/30/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2014/08/08/30/</id>
    <published>2014-08-09T00:45:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I turned 30.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I turned 30.</p>
]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[New hosting for Planeta Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2014/08/03/planetalinux-new-hosting/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2014/08/03/planetalinux-new-hosting/</id>
    <published>2014-08-03T19:50:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a very quick shout out.</p>
<p>A few weeks/months ago, <a href="http://planetalinux.org" target="_blank" rel="external">Planeta Linux</a> lost its hosting. As I’m less and less involved on third party projects, it was a bit hard for me to just put it somewhere else. <a href="http://blografia.net/vicm3/" target="_blank" rel="external">Víctor</a>, however, approached me and offered to pay for it. A few days later, we hosted Planeta Linux on one of his hosting instances. A big round of applause goes to him! He is the one making that community possible.</p>
<p>Over and out.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Just a very quick shout out.</p>
<p>A few weeks/months ago, <a href="http://planetalinux.org" target="_blank" rel="external">Planeta Linu]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="planetalinux" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/planetalinux/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[i3 respect]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2014/01/11/i3-respect/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2014/01/11/i3-respect/</id>
    <published>2014-01-11T19:02:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey <a href="http://michael.stapelberg.de/" target="_blank" rel="external">Michael Stapelberg</a>, thanks for creating <a href="http://i3wm.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">i3</a> and making me believe again that people have a clue and things can be done just right (specially when it comes to something easily done crappy like window managers). Thanks for just getting it all right, and not only from the software point of view, but also for the community, the style around it, etc. Kudos.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Hey <a href="http://michael.stapelberg.de/" target="_blank" rel="external">Michael Stapelberg</a>, thanks for creating <a href="http://i3]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="debian" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debian/"/>
    
      <category term="i3" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/i3/"/>
    
      <category term="respect" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/respect/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[FOSDEM 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2013/12/28/fosdem-2014/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2013/12/28/fosdem-2014/</id>
    <published>2013-12-28T20:17:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just booked my train tickets for <a href="http://fosdem.org/2014" target="_blank" rel="external">FOSDEM</a> 2014. Accommodation will be sorted out later.</p>
<p>This year I planned it well in advance to get decent prices for Thalys, unlike last year that we ended up riding the slow trains that stop in every single town in the Netherlands and Belgium taking forever.</p>
<p>See you there!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I just booked my train tickets for <a href="http://fosdem.org/2014" target="_blank" rel="external">FOSDEM</a> 2014. Accommodation will be]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="conferences" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/conferences/"/>
    
      <category term="debian" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debian/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[WWW::Tumblr 5.00]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/28/www-tumblr-5/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/28/www-tumblr-5/</id>
    <published>2013-08-28T05:27:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://damog.net/blog/www-tumblr.html" target="_blank" rel="external">A few years ago</a>, back when <a href="http://tumblr.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Tumblr</a> had not been valued a billion dollars, I wrote <tt>WWW::Tumblr</tt>, which was basically Perl bindings for their REST API. Then I forgot about it for a long time, then Yahoo! bought them or something like that. I ended up getting contacted by some Perl programmers, telling me that they were using the Perl module. Great! Anyway, following the general rule on Internet startups, Tumblr migrated most of their endpoints to OAuth and left a bunch of other resources changed to use an API key and others not. Joy. I gotta say that at this point I was’t interested on Tumblr too much, in spite of having a profile that followed a few very random blogs. But people were indeed interested on the module for their own stuff and I got contacted again a <a href="https://rt.cpan.org/Public/Bug/Display.html?id=86769" target="_blank" rel="external">few</a> <a href="https://github.com/damog/www-tumblr/issues/2" target="_blank" rel="external">times</a>.</p>
<p>Anyway, my coworker Fernando brought it to my attention more and more and I re-started working on my OAuth branch. A few weeks later now, I present you <a href="https://metacpan.org/module/WWW::Tumblr" target="_blank" rel="external">WWW::Tumblr</a> 5.00, which supports all of the <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/docs/en/api/v2" target="_blank" rel="external">methods</a> from the new Tumblr v2 API. During the development phase, Fernando tested a whole bunch, as well as <a href="http://yeupou.wordpress.com/2013/08/08/managing-a-tumblr-posts-queue-locally-with-tags/" target="_blank" rel="external">this other project</a>: I am very thankful for their help, since it took a while to properly make the API work as Tumblr does not seem to have the most compliant OAuth implementation of them all, and they seem to be quite unimpressed with questions and inquiries on their development group, but what are you gonna do about it, right, <em>sigh</em>.</p>
<p>Anyway, head to MetaCPAN to grab your copy today! And report bugs and stuff to the <a href="http://github.com/damog/www-tumblr" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub repo</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://damog.net/blog/www-tumblr.html" target="_blank" rel="external">A few years ago</a>, back when <a href="http://tumblr.com"]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="tumblr" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/tumblr/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[11 years in Freenode now]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/17/10-years-freenode/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/17/10-years-freenode/</id>
    <published>2013-08-18T00:29:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Somehow last year I missed the fact that I’ve been around <a href="http://freenode.net/" target="_blank" rel="external">Freenode</a> for 10 years. It is more than 11 years now at this point. Oh my! I understand this is nothing compared to the very old wolves in free software, but bear with me on this one :)</p>
<pre>
19:25 <damog> info
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- Information on Damog (account Damog):
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- Registered : Jun 26 23:45:11 2002 (11 years, 7 weeks, 5 days, 17:39:50 ago)
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- Last addr  : ~dm@debian/developer/damog
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- vHost      : debian/developer/damog
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- Last seen  : now
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- Logins from: damog
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- Nicks      : Damog
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- Email      : damog@damog.net
19:25 -NickServ(NickServ@services.)- *** End of Info ***
</damog></pre>


]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Somehow last year I missed the fact that I’ve been around <a href="http://freenode.net/" target="_blank" rel="external">Freenode</a> for ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="freenode" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/freenode/"/>
    
      <category term="irc" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/irc/"/>
    
      <category term="linux" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/linux/"/>
    
      <category term="opensource" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/opensource/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/13/29/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/13/29/</id>
    <published>2013-08-14T00:05:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As of this past August 8th, I am now officially 29 years old. It seems like it was just yesterday when I was blogging about my <a href="/blog/my-birthday.html">20th birthday</a>, right? Well yeah, no, it wasn’t exactly yesterday :)</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>As of this past August 8th, I am now officially 29 years old. It seems like it was just yesterday when I was blogging about my <a href="/]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="29" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/29/"/>
    
      <category term="life" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/life/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[One year]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/06/one-year-at-booking/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2013/08/06/one-year-at-booking/</id>
    <published>2013-08-07T03:17:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A year ago today, I <a href="/blog/another-day-another-dawn.html">started working</a> for <a href="http://booking.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Booking.com</a>. I wish I could say that the time has flown by, but it really hasn’t. It has been one hell of a ride on all fronts: work, learning experiences, friends, but specially at home, since working for this company didn’t come without a complete life change. So far so good, and for that I’m grateful :)</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>A year ago today, I <a href="/blog/another-day-another-dawn.html">started working</a> for <a href="http://booking.com" target="_blank" re]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="amsterdam" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/amsterdam/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="work" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/work/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Debian meetup in Utrecht, The Netherlands]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2013/04/18/debian-meetup-in-utrecht-2013/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2013/04/18/debian-meetup-in-utrecht-2013/</id>
    <published>2013-04-19T02:28:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This next Tuesday, April 23rd, 2013, a few of us Debian people in the Netherlands will get together for beer and keysigning in Belgisch Bier Café Olivier in Utrecht. If you are in the area, feel free to come, have a beer or two and mingle!</p>
<p>Find the exact details in <a href="http://lists.debian.org/debian-events-nl/2013/04/msg00005.html" target="_blank" rel="external">this debian-events-nl mail</a>.</p>
<p>See you there!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>This next Tuesday, April 23rd, 2013, a few of us Debian people in the Netherlands will get together for beer and keysigning in Belgisch B]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="debian" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debian/"/>
    
      <category term="netherlands" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/netherlands/"/>
    
      <category term="utrecht" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/utrecht/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[FOSDEM 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2013/01/26/fosdem/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2013/01/26/fosdem/</id>
    <published>2013-01-26T22:57:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the conferences that I always wanted to attend is <a href="https://fosdem.org" target="_blank" rel="external">FOSDEM</a>. Now, since I live <i>close</i> enough to Brussels, it’d be a gigantic letdown not to make it there next weekend. I plan to be in Brussels Fri to Sun, see you there!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>One of the conferences that I always wanted to attend is <a href="https://fosdem.org" target="_blank" rel="external">FOSDEM</a>. Now, sin]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="conferences" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/conferences/"/>
    
      <category term="debian" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debian/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Another day, another dawn]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/08/18/another-day-another-dawn/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/08/18/another-day-another-dawn/</id>
    <published>2012-08-18T19:04:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started working for <a href="http://www.booking.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Booking.com</a> two weeks ago now. These last two months have been probably the most chaotic and hectic in a long time from what I remember in my life. I left New York City, chilled out in Mexico City for several weeks and then finally relocated to beautiful Amsterdam. The decision of leaving New York was not simple, but I decided to take on new challenges, one cycle had ended for me and it was time for me to move on.</p>
<p>The change has not been easy, but it hasn’t been bad at all. I knew that coming from a very mutating startup in New York City into a company with presence in dozens of countries and several thousand employees was not gonna be a simple change. I decided to proceed with this because I want to learn. I want to learn how other businesses use technology, specially the kind that I’m most interested on, to become successful. I want to understand how they operate. I want to help a company succeed, take on new technology lessons and learn from more experienced peers. Thankfully, I’m not financially burdened and I’m able to make this decision myself without affecting (too much) others. I wanted the adventure (again) of relocating to a new country and making it to a company that has been successful for so many years, hugely based in Perl, who has contributed <a href="http://news.perlfoundation.org/2012/01/bookingcom-sponsors-100000-to.html" target="_blank" rel="external">boldly</a> to its community, with so many great Perl developers in the mix, etc., just made it all worth it.</p>
<p>Being a new guy is never easy, and I haven’t really been one of those often. I wish I knew how a lot of things work already, so I was able to contribute faster. At the end, this is all about a business and it’s about what developers and engineers do to contribute, to give back, to produce something that ends up as revenue and profit, and I want to do just that. Benefits and perks are always nice, but what I really want is prove to myself and to those who hired me the kind of competent talent that I am.</p>
<p>If you can understand Spanish, this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/embed/KHXiLURi4lA" target="_blank" rel="external">video</a> explains it better. </p>
<p>Oh and yeah, I turned 28 during my first week of work here in the Netherlands and was lucky enough to have a very happy one with plenty of hopes and goals.</p>
<p>Cheers.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I started working for <a href="http://www.booking.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Booking.com</a> two weeks ago now. These last two m]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="amsterdam" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/amsterdam/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="work" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/work/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[I'm a brogrammer, brah!]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/07/27/im-a-brogrammer-brah/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/07/27/im-a-brogrammer-brah/</id>
    <published>2012-07-27T18:45:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My professional career has been kind of an interesting one. I believe that when I diverted from being a completely stereotype of a geek, my career as an IT professional really took off. Or at least, the real experience: that experience that no words can describe on a resume but that only you have within, that experience that only comes up when you’re facing a real-life problem and no interviews or screening processes or algorithms challenges and tests can really discover. That experience really started emerging when, ironically, I started looking at work as a medium to get to a more fulfilled life, instead of the life itself. I stopped attending conferences for fun or just hacking mandatory GPL software, and started developing a different array of preferences. I believe that when I started doing that, I started learning more in favor of my previous employer. I didn’t see everything through the pragmatism of what other programmers (specially free software advocates that I was mostly involved with six to seven years ago) would think and started to enjoy what I do and how I did it. I started to learn from other people, to see how real life problems are approached and how they’re attacked and thankfully I did learn how a lot of those are solved. And how the entire scheme actually pays off.</p>
<p>I come with this preliminar description of my current professional career because I read, and you should too, a great masterpiece of a ranting about the <em>brogrammer</em> and geek/nerd stereotype overall, by Perl guru <a href="http://shadow.cat/blog/matt-s-trout/" target="_blank" rel="external">mst</a>, called <a href="http://shadow.cat/blog/matt-s-trout/neither-nerd-nor-bro/" target="_blank" rel="external">Neither Nerd nor Bro</a>. In it, he rants extensively about this <em>brogrammer</em> term and the whole nerd culture. Go read it. I’ll wait here.</p>
<p>You done? Good. I am of course <strong>not</strong> a brogrammer, don’t let the title of this post trick you. I believe that such a term is associated to failure just like a company could pretend to be cool enough to call its programmers something like ninjas or rockstars. Recipe for disaster. Why would anyone think of himself like a rockstar or a ninja? What’s the point for that? And is this only a recruiting technique by that people who don’t have a single hint of clue of technical knowledge and think they’re getting to real and actual A-player programmers?</p>
<p>I cannot do anything else but agree with what mst states. And I think the best programmers are those who don’t consider themselves like it. Good programmers, just like everyone else in life, are those who enjoy life and not those who pretend to be something they might not even be. I stopped attending conferences when I learned that I would enjoy seeing people kick each other on the groin more so I started spending money in watching <a href="http://ufc.com" target="_blank" rel="external">UFC</a> pay-per-views and whenever possible, come to live shows (believe me, they are expensive). But do not fail to encapsulate me on a “I’m so not a nerd that I want to choke you until you pass out to prove my manliness” speech. I also continued developing my passion for chess by joining a chess club and enjoyed chess tournaments. And when I started doing all of this alternative activities, my work, I believe, saw a peek in productivity. Doing what you love best, does affect your skills at work.</p>
<p>While the whole <em>brogrammer</em> term might be an entire joke, calling programmers rockstars is a fact and a reality and I couldn’t do anything more but despise those using the term and even more those owning it. In the hotbed that the whole Web startups have created in places like New York or Silicon Valley, you can be approached under those terms. As someone who has interviewed people for positions before and who has effectively hired people, I can say that you can definitively benefit more from passioned people who have other interests than those who are just pretentious fucks. I like people who might spend more time thinking about how to put that passion into a full-time endeavour. Those are legit. People who do what they love are the real deal. People who dream to do what they love and never lose motivation are the real deal as well.</p>
<p>Please be genuine. Peace.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>My professional career has been kind of an interesting one. I believe that when I diverted from being a completely stereotype of a geek, ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="life" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="rants" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/rants/"/>
    
      <category term="startups" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/startups/"/>
    
      <category term="work" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/work/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[I quit]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/07/25/i-quit/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/07/25/i-quit/</id>
    <published>2012-07-25T17:35:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just recently quit my job at the startup company I had been working in for almost five years. In startup terms, such long time might be a whole lifetime, but in my case, I grew liking it more and more as the years came, I had evolved from being just another engineer, to lead a team of seven great developers, with decision-making tasks and strategy planning for our technical infrastructure. It’s been such a great long teaching journey that I’m nothing but pleased with my own performance, <a href="http://axiombox.com/lessons-learned-and-real-experience/" target="_blank" rel="external">learned lessons</a> and skills and all I provided and was provided by the project.</p>
<p>Leaving a city like New York is not an easy task. You have it all there, you start making a life and suddenly, before you know it, you already have a bunch of ties to the place, people, leases, important dates, all kinds of shit. Seriously, all kinds of crazy ass shit start to fill up your baggage. You wake up everyday to get into the subway and commute surrounded by all of this people that are just like you: so similar yet so immensely different. No, leaving the city is not an easy task, it’s not something to take lightly. You know how people just say “my cycle has ended in this place” as an euphemism not to end in bad terms with anyone? Well, ending a cycle is indeed a reality, I got to a point where I felt like I needed to head into a different direction, take on new challenges and overall, peace out and hope the best to everyone, specially to myself.</p>
<p>This was me, on my last day at work, last Friday of June:</p>
<p><a href="http://damog.net/old/axiombox/2012/07/damog-respect1.jpg" target="_blank" rel="external"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1322" title="damog-respect" src="http://damog.net/old/axiombox/2012/07/damog-respect1.jpg" alt="" width="534" height="426"></a></p>
<p>(Some) people seem to be anxious to know what I’m doing next, and my answer is, go mind your own fucking business. However, life is short and I would love to do any of the following:</p>
<p><ul><br>    <li>Go back to Brazil again, now as a blue belt in Brazilian jiujitsu, and train non-stop in Rio, this time as a local. I happened to come to Rio last November (as a four stripe white belt) and it’d been a great experience, with the <a href="http://www.connectionrio.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Connection Rio</a> guys. I kind of regretted not staying any longer, as a lot of people use to do, maybe three months. You don’t get to do anything else but train and roll with black belts on a daily basis, eat the healthy good stuff that a wonderful country like Brazil has to offer, hang out with amazing people and chill the fuck out all day long.</li><br>    <li>Make a road trip through Central America and get to know all of those countries where I’ve never been to even when I’ve travelled extensively around them for the last few years. I would head to the southernmost tip of Mexico and then take a bus to backpack travel in the cities all the way to Panama. Beer all along, a lot of swimming, plenty of heaven.</li><br>    <li>Head to any Russian consulate so I can get an entry visa for their amazing country and travel to any chess club on any of its big cities. Or maybe Hungary (do I need a visa to visit it?). Stay on small hostels where all I could use is a few good chess books and a chessboard, absorbe myself into chess sounds like a dream come true.</li><br>    <li>Stop procrastinating and write all the good Perl stuff I’ve wanting to do on my own time. All of those good projects I always thought of and only had opportunity to try at work but not on a giving-back-to-the-community kind of way.</li><br></ul><br>Decisions, decisions…</p>
<p>For the time being, I’m chilling with my people, friends and family in beautiful Mexico City. I’ve been doing so for the entire month of July and I couldn’t be more content. August will see my 28th birthday and as I approach thirty, I believe I need to continue moving forward.</p>
<p>This stupid world is a tiny place and our lives are short, I for one, will definitively try to take the bull by the horns.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading, more updates soon. Peace.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I just recently quit my job at the startup company I had been working in for almost five years. In startup terms, such long time might be]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="bjj" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/bjj/"/>
    
      <category term="life" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="work" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/work/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Deploying a Dancer app on Heroku]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/07/16/deploying-a-dancer-app-on-heroku/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/07/16/deploying-a-dancer-app-on-heroku/</id>
    <published>2012-07-17T02:03:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There’s a <a href="http://blog.kraih.com/mojolicious-in-the-cloud-hello-heroku" target="_blank" rel="external">few</a> different posts out there on how to run Perl apps, such as Mojolicious-based, on Heroku, but I’d like to show how to deploy a <a href="http://perldancer.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Perl Dancer</a> application on <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Heroku</a>.</p>
<p>The startup script of a Dancer application (bin/app.pl) can be used as a <a href="http://plackperl.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">PSGI</a> file. With that in mind, I was able to take the good work of <a href="http://bulknews.typepad.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Miyagawa’s</a> <a href="https://github.com/miyagawa/heroku-buildpack-perl" target="_blank" rel="external">Heroku buildpack</a> for general PSGI apps and hack it a little bit to use Dancer’s, specifically. What I like about Miyagawa’s approach is that uses the fantastic <a href="http://search.cpan.org/~miyagawa/App-cpanminus-1.5015/bin/cpanm" target="_blank" rel="external">cpanm</a> and makes it available within your application, instead of the monotonous cpan, to solve dependencies.</p>
<p>Let’s make a simple Dancer app to show how to make this happen:</p>
<p><code lang="bash"><br>/tmp $ dancer -a heroku</code></p>
<ul>
<li>heroku</li>
<li>heroku/bin</li>
<li>heroku/bin/app.pl</li>
<li>heroku/config.yml</li>
<li>heroku/environments</li>
<li>heroku/environments/development.yml</li>
<li>heroku/environments/production.yml</li>
<li>heroku/views</li>
<li>heroku/views/index.tt</li>
<li>heroku/views/layouts</li>
<li>heroku/views/layouts/main.tt</li>
<li>heroku/MANIFEST.SKIP</li>
<li>heroku/lib<br>heroku/lib/</li>
<li>heroku/lib/heroku.pm</li>
<li>heroku/public</li>
<li>heroku/public/css</li>
<li>heroku/public/css/style.css</li>
<li>heroku/public/css/error.css</li>
<li>heroku/public/images</li>
<li>heroku/public/500.html</li>
<li>heroku/public/404.html</li>
<li>heroku/public/dispatch.fcgi</li>
<li>heroku/public/dispatch.cgi</li>
<li>heroku/public/javascripts</li>
<li>heroku/public/javascripts/jquery.js</li>
<li>heroku/t</li>
<li>heroku/t/002_index_route.t</li>
<li>heroku/t/001_base.t</li>
<li>heroku/Makefile.PL<br></li>
</ul>
<p>Now, you already know that by firing ‘perl bin/app.pl’ you can get your development server up and running. So I’ll just proceed to show how to make this work on Heroku, you should already have your development environment configured for it:</p>
<p><code lang="bash"><br>/tmp $ cd heroku/<br>/tmp/heroku $ git init<br>Initialized empty Git repository in /private/tmp/heroku/.git/<br>/tmp/heroku :master $ git add .<br>/tmp/heroku :master $ git commit -a -m ‘Dancer on Heroku’<br>[master (root-commit) 6c0c55a] Dancer on Heroku<br>22 files changed, 809 insertions(+), 0 deletions(-)<br>create mode 100644 MANIFEST<br>create mode 100644 MANIFEST.SKIP<br>create mode 100644 Makefile.PL<br>create mode 100755 bin/app.pl<br>create mode 100644 config.yml<br>create mode 100644 environments/development.yml<br>create mode 100644 environments/production.yml<br>create mode 100644 lib/heroku.pm<br>create mode 100644 public/404.html<br>create mode 100644 public/500.html<br>create mode 100644 public/css/error.css<br>create mode 100644 public/css/style.css<br>create mode 100755 public/dispatch.cgi<br>create mode 100755 public/dispatch.fcgi<br>create mode 100644 public/favicon.ico<br>create mode 100644 public/images/perldancer-bg.jpg<br>create mode 100644 public/images/perldancer.jpg<br>create mode 100644 public/javascripts/jquery.js<br>create mode 100644 t/001_base.t<br>create mode 100644 t/002_index_route.t<br>create mode 100644 views/index.tt<br>create mode 100644 views/layouts/main.tt<br>/tmp/heroku :master $<br></code></p>
<p>And now, run <tt>heroku create</tt>, please note the buildpack URL, <tt><a href="http://github.com/damog/heroku-buildpack-perl.git" target="_blank" rel="external">http://github.com/damog/heroku-buildpack-perl.git</a></tt>:</p>
<p><code lang="bash"><br>/tmp/heroku :master $ heroku create —stack cedar —buildpack <a href="http://github.com/damog/heroku-buildpack-perl.git" target="_blank" rel="external">http://github.com/damog/heroku-buildpack-perl.git</a><br>Creating blazing-beach-7280… done, stack is cedar<br><a href="http://blazing-beach-7280.herokuapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">http://blazing-beach-7280.herokuapp.com/</a> | git@heroku.com:blazing-beach-7280.git<br>Git remote heroku added<br>/tmp/heroku :master $<br></code></p>
<p>And just push:</p>
<p><code lang="bash"><br>/tmp/heroku :master $ git push heroku master<br>Counting objects: 34, done.<br>Delta compression using up to 4 threads.<br>Compressing objects: 100% (30/30), done.<br>Writing objects: 100% (34/34), 40.60 KiB, done.<br>Total 34 (delta 3), reused 0 (delta 0)</code></p>
<p>——-&gt; Heroku receiving push<br>——-&gt; Fetching custom buildpack… done<br>——-&gt; Perl/PSGI Dancer! app detected<br>——-&gt; Bootstrapping cpanm<br>Successfully installed JSON-PP-2.27200<br>Successfully installed CPAN-Meta-YAML-0.008<br>Successfully installed Parse-CPAN-Meta-1.4404 (upgraded from 1.39)<br>Successfully installed version-0.99 (upgraded from 0.77)<br>Successfully installed Module-Metadata-1.000009<br>Successfully installed CPAN-Meta-Requirements-2.122<br>Successfully installed CPAN-Meta-2.120921<br>Successfully installed Perl-OSType-1.002<br>Successfully installed ExtUtils-CBuilder-0.280205 (upgraded from 0.2602)<br>Successfully installed ExtUtils-ParseXS-3.15 (upgraded from 2.2002)<br>Successfully installed Module-Build-0.4001 (upgraded from 0.340201)<br>Successfully installed App-cpanminus-1.5015<br>12 distributions installed<br>——-&gt; Installing dependencies<br>Successfully installed ExtUtils-MakeMaker-6.62 (upgraded from 6.55_02)<br>Successfully installed YAML-0.84<br>Successfully installed Test-Simple-0.98 (upgraded from 0.92)<br>Successfully installed Try-Tiny-0.11<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Server-Simple-0.44<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Server-Simple-PSGI-0.14<br>Successfully installed URI-1.60<br>Successfully installed Test-Tester-0.108<br>Successfully installed Test-NoWarnings-1.04<br>Successfully installed Test-Deep-0.110<br>Successfully installed LWP-MediaTypes-6.02<br>Successfully installed Encode-Locale-1.03<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Date-6.02<br>Successfully installed HTML-Tagset-3.20<br>Successfully installed HTML-Parser-3.69<br>Successfully installed Compress-Raw-Bzip2-2.052 (upgraded from 2.020)<br>Successfully installed Compress-Raw-Zlib-2.054 (upgraded from 2.020)<br>Successfully installed IO-Compress-2.052 (upgraded from 2.020)<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Message-6.03<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Body-1.15<br>Successfully installed MIME-Types-1.35<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Negotiate-6.01<br>Successfully installed File-Listing-6.04<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Daemon-6.01<br>Successfully installed Net-HTTP-6.03<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Cookies-6.01<br>Successfully installed WWW-RobotRules-6.02<br>Successfully installed libwww-perl-6.04<br>Successfully installed Dancer-1.3097<br>29 distributions installed<br>——-&gt; Installing Starman<br>Successfully installed Test-Requires-0.06<br>Successfully installed Hash-MultiValue-0.12<br>Successfully installed Devel-StackTrace-1.27<br>Successfully installed Test-SharedFork-0.20<br>Successfully installed Test-TCP-1.16<br>Successfully installed Class-Inspector-1.27<br>Successfully installed File-ShareDir-1.03<br>Successfully installed Filesys-Notify-Simple-0.08<br>Successfully installed Devel-StackTrace-AsHTML-0.11<br>Successfully installed Plack-0.9989<br>Successfully installed Net-Server-2.006<br>Successfully installed HTTP-Parser-XS-0.14<br>Successfully installed Data-Dump-1.21<br>Successfully installed Starman-0.3001<br>14 distributions installed<br>——-&gt; Discovering process types<br>Procfile declares types -&amp;gt; (none)<br>Default types for Perl/PSGI Dancer! -&amp;gt; web<br>——-&gt; Compiled slug size is 2.7MB<br>——-&gt; Launching… done, v4<br><a href="http://blazing-beach-7280.herokuapp.com" target="_blank" rel="external">http://blazing-beach-7280.herokuapp.com</a> deployed to Heroku</p>
<p>To git@heroku.com:blazing-beach-7280.git</p>
<ul>
<li>[new branch] master -&amp;gt; master<br>/tmp/heroku :master $<br></li>
</ul>
<p>And you can confirm it works:</p>
<p></p><p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://damog.net/old/stereonaut/2012/07/Screen-Shot-2012-07-16-at-8.54.03-PM.png" target="_blank" rel="external"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1313" title="Screen Shot 2012-07-16 at 8.54.03 PM" src="http://damog.net/old/stereonaut/2012/07/Screen-Shot-2012-07-16-at-8.54.03-PM.png" alt="" width="538" height="346"></a></p><br>Please note that the environment it runs on is “deployment”. The backend server it uses is the great Starman, also by the great Miyagawa.<p></p>
<p>Now, if you add or change dependencies on Makefile.PL, next time you push, those will get updated.</p>
<p>Very cool, right? :)</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>There’s a <a href="http://blog.kraih.com/mojolicious-in-the-cloud-hello-heroku" target="_blank" rel="external">few</a> different posts ou]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="dancer" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/dancer/"/>
    
      <category term="heroku" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/heroku/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Ruby and libv8: Exactly my feelings]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/04/23/ruby-and-libv8-exactly-my-feelings/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/04/23/ruby-and-libv8-exactly-my-feelings/</id>
    <published>2012-04-23T18:33:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" style="-webkit-user-select: none;" src="http://dan.sel.ec/kimura_images/KimuraLIBV8.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Thanks to my coworker <a href="http://dantylkowski.com/" target="_blank">Dan</a> for making a whole bunch of these based on our day job adventures :)</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" style="-webkit-user-select: none;" src="http://dan.sel.ec/kimura_images/KimuraLIBV8.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Thanks t]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="feces" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/feces/"/>
    
      <category term="libv8" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/libv8/"/>
    
      <category term="ruby" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/ruby/"/>
    
      <category term="v8" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/v8/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Geo::PostalCode::NoDB 0.01]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/21/geo-postalcode-nodb-001/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/21/geo-postalcode-nodb-001/</id>
    <published>2012-03-21T17:19:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://metacpan.org/module/Geo::PostalCode" target="_blank" rel="external">Geo::PostalCode</a> is a great Perl module. It lets you find surrounding postal areas (zip codes) around a given an amount of miles (radius), calculate distance between them, among other nice features. Sadly, I couldn’t get it to work with updated data and because the file its Berkely DB installer was producing was not being recognized by its parser, which bases off on <a href="http://perldoc.perl.org/DB_File.html" target="_blank" rel="external">DB_File</a>. Since I was able to find <a href="http://damog.net/files/misc/zipcodes-csv-10-Aug-2004.zip" target="_blank" rel="external">working data</a> for the source of zip codes, I ended up hacking the module and producing a version with no Berkeley DB support.</p>
<p>So basically, and taken from the POD:</p>
<p><blockquote>RATIONALE BEHIND NO BERKELEY DB<br>On a busy day at work, I couldn’t get Geo::PostalCode to work with newer data (the data source <a href="http://search.cpan.org/~tjmather/" target="_blank" rel="external">TJMATHER</a> points <a href="http://cpansearch.perl.org/src/TJMATHER/Geo-PostalCode-0.07/INSTALL" target="_blank" rel="external">to</a> is no longer available), so the tests shipped with his module pass, but trying to use real data no longer seems to work. DB_File marked the <a href="http://search.cpan.org/~tjmather/Geo-PostalCode-0.07/lib/Geo/PostalCode/InstallDB.pm" target="_blank" rel="external">Geo::PostalCode::InstallDB</a> output file as invalid type or format. If you don’t run into that issue by not wanting to use this module, please drop <a href="http://damog.net/" target="_blank" rel="external">me</a> a note! I would love to learn how other people made it work.</blockquote></p>
<p>So, in order to get my shit done, I decided to create this module. Loading the whole data into memory from the class constructor has been proven to be enough for massive usage (citation needed) on a <a href="http://perldancer.org" target="_blank" rel="external">Dancer</a> application where this module is instantiated only once.</p>
<p><tt>$ sudo cpanm <a href="https://metacpan.org/module/DAMOG/Geo-PostalCode-NoDB-0.01/lib/Geo/PostalCode/NoDB.pm" target="_blank" rel="external">Geo::PostalCode::NoDB</a></tt> now!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://metacpan.org/module/Geo::PostalCode" target="_blank" rel="external">Geo::PostalCode</a> is a great Perl module. It lets ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="berkeley db" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/berkeley-db/"/>
    
      <category term="cpan" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/cpan/"/>
    
      <category term="hack" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/hack/"/>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="postal code" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/postal-code/"/>
    
      <category term="zipcodes" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/zipcodes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Feedbag released under MIT license]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/16/feedbag-mit-license/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/16/feedbag-mit-license/</id>
    <published>2012-03-16T16:55:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was contacted by <a href="http://pivotallabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Pivotal Labs</a> regarding licensing of <a href="https://rubygems.org/gems/feedbag" target="_blank" rel="external">Feedbag</a>. I guess releasing open source software as <a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html" target="_blank" rel="external">GPL</a> only makes sense if you continue to live under a rock. I’ve bumped the version to 0.9 and released it under <a href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.html" target="_blank" rel="external">MIT license</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://axiombox.com/feedbag" target="_blank" rel="external">Feedbag</a> 1.0, which I plan to work on during the following days will bring in a brand new shiny backend powered by <a href="http://nokogiri.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Nokogiri</a>, instead of <a href="http://hpricot.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hpricot</a> (I mean, give me a break, I’m trying to catch up with the Ruby community, after all I’m primarily a Perl guy :D) and hopefully I will be able to recreate most of the <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20090518022508/http://diveintomark.org/tests/client/autodiscovery/" target="_blank" rel="external">feed auto-discovery test suite</a> that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Pilgrim_(software_developer)" target="_blank" rel="external">Mark Pilgrim</a> retired (<a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/410GoneThoughtsOnMarkDiveintomarkPilgrimsAndWhysInfosuicides.aspx" target="_blank" rel="external">410 Gone</a>) when he committed <a href="http://ctmiller.net/2011/10/lets-discuss-infosuicide/" target="_blank" rel="external">infosuicide</a>.</p>
<p>Have a good weekend!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I was contacted by <a href="http://pivotallabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Pivotal Labs</a> regarding licensing of <a href="http]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="copyright" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/copyright/"/>
    
      <category term="feed" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/feed/"/>
    
      <category term="feedbag" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/feedbag/"/>
    
      <category term="gpl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/gpl/"/>
    
      <category term="mit" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/mit/"/>
    
      <category term="ruby" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/ruby/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Is GitHub really necessary for your startup engineering team?]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/11/is-github-really-necessary-for-your-startup-engineering-team/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/11/is-github-really-necessary-for-your-startup-engineering-team/</id>
    <published>2012-03-12T05:52:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last few months, I’ve been ranting a little too much with <a href="http://selectablemedia.com" target="_blank" rel="external">our</a> engineering team about <a href="http://github.com" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a>. These rantings, of course, didn’t come out of the blue. I haven’t been too satisfied with GitHub’s reliability lately since we use it for our daily development and constant deployment on our different staging environments and our own operation has been affected by their recent multiple technical difficulties. This has led me to analyze whether we really need them, why we started paying for their service in the first place and if it’s really necessary for our product development in the first place.</p>
<p>Being an startup that originated its main product on Ruby and Ruby on Rails, some of our initial engineers were more oriented towards Ruby and open source technologies. We started using GitHub because it was the natural and de facto choice. Creation of repositories and private contributors was easy and would put you up to speed with collaboration. As we grew in developers count, our repositories did too as well as different projects. We even brought a system administrator in place. Do we still need GitHub right now? I won’t be dropping Git as our main version control system, but what has GitHub provided my company and project in exchange for the $200 we are paying them every month? Is it only hype for a company to use it for their internal repositories? Or is it hype to use them for their open repositories?</p>
<p>The lack of site reliability on their side is what has led me thinking about whether we should still use them. What really concerns me is that they seem to have operational issues on a daily basis, they’re constantly announcing new hires, new pub meetings and new <a href="http://octodex.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Octocat</a> designs, and little effort has been shown about the technical operations. It sometimes amazes me how people is so much in love with GitHub to the point where I even find “liked” articles on their feed on Google Reader whenever they announce downtimes and br0kenage (now +1’s). It’s like people enjoy what’s wrong.</p>
<p>Are we using their issues functionality? The nice thread comments per commit, per line? Are we using pull requests? Are we using any of their actual offering compared to what a native Git server setup offers? No. The only thing is just pretty much the collaboration management, and even then, the “Groups” feature per organization is still lacking. The only main feature we use is the web browsing for the repos, which we can do with open source tools anyway. At the end, there’s other great GUIs for Git we also use on a daily basis, such as <a href="http://gitx.frim.nl/" target="_blank" rel="external">GitX</a> or <a href="http://www.git-tower.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Tower</a> (and for now, yes, <a href="http://mac.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub’s GUI client</a>).</p>
<p>The issue they were attacked with last week makes me wonder whether they are the right organization to give us version control system services or we’re just using them because we haven’t know any better or even looked at our own resources (people and machines). Someone got commit access to an open source repository. What if it would have been a malicious user getting access to private repositories where passwords and other sensitive are stored? How serious is this company? $200 is not much for a startup to spend on a neat service, but when that provider seems to be more concerned about stickers or beer than fixing their tech operations from the inside out is when it gets worrying. I like to see how other similar services we’re using compare to GitHub, how stable they feel and how notorious that reliability is shown. For example, <a href="http://newrelic.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">New Relic</a> which we also use, seems rock solid and they don’t show issues at all. What’s the difference here anyway?</p>
<p>Site reliability is tricky anyway: when it’s faulty, it shows and screams because it affects business operations and reaches the entire company; when it’s working perfectly, the way it should, you can barely realize people are doing an stupendous job. GitHub, however, doesn’t seem to have this clear.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>For the last few months, I’ve been ranting a little too much with <a href="http://selectablemedia.com" target="_blank" rel="external">our]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="git" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/git/"/>
    
      <category term="github" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/github/"/>
    
      <category term="site reliability" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/site-reliability/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Lessons learned and real experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/05/lessons-learned-and-real-experience/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2012/03/05/lessons-learned-and-real-experience/</id>
    <published>2012-03-05T22:44:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been busy.</p>
<p><a href="http://selectablemedia.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">We</a>‘ve been building a next generation video ad serving platform with all of lessons and experience we’ve gained over the last couple of years and specially over last one. In an industry where there’s too much client demand there’s only a few key supply players doing a good job and we’ve identified strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats. We’ve kept ourselves busy.</p>
<p>Over the course of last year, especially on the second half and as far as this first quarter of 2012 has been running, aims for a new better product have made me reconsider what I thought I knew and what I thought I had to learn on an engineering point of view, about how to build not only regular or good software, but enterprise software. Having a startup background where dynamics are key, we’ve shifted into a more concise, long-term, sustainable technology where pieces need not to change easily, but at the same time, provide flexibility, customizable solutions for clients’ needs and that would allow us to continue growing.</p>
<p>Question for me has been whether all of what I thought I knew about Web dynamics, engineering and technology is what I really thought it was. How do you get to the point where you start using some sort of product to enable you to build another. How is that decision made in your head. What business decisions are made that affect the technology stack on the technology your peers are building, on the product you are taking care of to produce something usable. How are those decisions considered from a technology point of view, are they just passed along and executed or do they really carry along considerations from all points of the company.</p>
<p>A modern life Web engineer does not only write software. That person should also understand how the entire business stack works, why are positions covered around him and how are those dots connecting to provide a good solution for some one who pays to use it. The engineer has to understand that very well.</p>
<p>It’s amazing the amount of strategies that I’ve personally met and thought of over the time. Real life experience is invaluable, but basic understanding of how things work is what enables that, and some people sometimes seem to forget that. Are you paying overpriced developers because you’re using hyped technology? Are you putting enough thought on what you are building and what could lead to in terms of those bricks.</p>
<p>It is not a myth that when you learn and increase your knowledge on something, something else seems to open up and leave your mind with more questions. Learning more makes you realize you’re ignorant. And it’s only the ability and willingness to continue learning that would lead you to a much better thought process that could even eventually make you think that the answer to the question was just right there from the very beginning, from the basics.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I’ve been busy.</p>
<p><a href="http://selectablemedia.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">We</a>‘ve been building a next generation vid]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="life" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="tech" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/tech/"/>
    
      <category term="work" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/work/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[RVM + Rake tasks on Cron jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2011/08/02/rvm-rake-tasks-on-cron-jobs/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2011/08/02/rvm-rake-tasks-on-cron-jobs/</id>
    <published>2011-08-02T15:57:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://rvm.beginrescueend.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">RVM</a> hates my guts. And it doesn’t matter, because I hate RVM back even more. Since I was technologically raised by aging wolfs, I have strong reasons to believe that you just shouldn’t have mixed versions of software on your production systems, specially, if a lot of things are poorly tested, like <a href="http://rubygems.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">most of Ruby libraries</a>, aren’t backward compatible. I was raised on a world where everything worked greatly because the good folks at projects like <a href="http://www.debian.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Debian</a> or <a href="http://search.cpan.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Perl</a> have some of the greatest QA processes of all time, hands down. So, when someone introduces a thing like RVM which not only promotes having hundreds of different versions of the same software, both on development, testing and production environments, but also encourages poor quality looking back and looking forward, there isn’t anything else but to lose faith in humanity.</p>
<p>But enough for ranting.</p>
<p>I had to deliver this side project that works with the <a href="http://dev.twitter.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Twitter API</a> and the only requirement pretty much was that it had to be both run from the shell but also loaded as a class within a Ruby script. And so I did everything locally with my great local installation of Ruby 1.8.7. When it came the time to load on the testing/production server I found myself on a situation where pathetic RVM was installed. After spending hours trying to accommodate my changes to run properly with Ruby 1.9.2, I set up a cron job using crontab to run my shit every now and then. And the shit wasn’t even running properly. Basically, my crontab line looked something like this:</p>
<p><code lang="bash"><br><em>/30 </em> <em> </em> * cd /home/david/myproject &amp;&amp; rake awesome_task<br></code></p>
<p>And that was failing, crontab was returning some crazy shit like “Ruby and/or RubyGems cannot find the rake gem”. Seriously? Then I thought, well, maybe my environment needs to be loaded and whatever, so I made a bash script with something like this:</p>
<p><code lang="bash"></code></p>
<h1 id="!/bin/bash">!/bin/bash</h1><p>cd /home/david/myproject<br>/full/path/to/rvm/bin/rake -f Rakefile awesome_task<br></p>
<p>And that was still failing with the same error. So after trying to find out how cron jobs and crontab load Bash source files, I took a look at <a href="http://wiki.debian.org/DotFiles" target="_blank" rel="external">how Debian starts its shell</a> upon login. And while that didn’t tell me that much that I didn’t know, I went to look at the system-wide /etc/profile and found a gem, a wonderful directory /etc/profile.d/ where a single shitty file was sitting, smiling back at me, like waiting for me to find it out and swear on all problems in life: rvm.sh. /etc/profile is not being loaded when I just run /bin/bash by my crappy script, only when I log in, I should’ve known this. Doesn’t RVM solve the issue of having system-wide installations so the user doesn’t have to deal with, you know, anything outside of his own /home ?</p>
<p>So I had to go ahead and do:</p>
<p><code lang="bash"></code></p>
<h1 id="!/bin/bash-1">!/bin/bash</h1><p>source /etc/profile<br>cd /home/david/myproject<br>/full/path/to/rvm/bin/rake -f Rakefile awesome_task<br></p>
<p>And hours later I was able to continue with work. Maybe this will help some poor bastard like myself on similar situation on the future.</p>
<p>Of course one can argue that I could’ve installed my own RVM and its Ruby versions, but why, oh why, if it was, apparently, already there. Why would I have to fiddle with the Ruby installations if all I want is get my shit done and head to City Bakery where I can spend that money I just earned on chocolate cookies? My work is pretty simple to run with pretty much any ancient version of Ruby, nothing fancy (unless you call MongoMapper fancy). RVM is a great project that doesn’t solve an issue, but just hides some really fucked up shit on the Ruby community.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://rvm.beginrescueend.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">RVM</a> hates my guts. And it doesn’t matter, because I hate RVM]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="cron" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/cron/"/>
    
      <category term="crontab" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/crontab/"/>
    
      <category term="rake" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/rake/"/>
    
      <category term="ruby" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/ruby/"/>
    
      <category term="rubygems" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/rubygems/"/>
    
      <category term="rvm" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/rvm/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[DebConf 11]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2011/07/01/debconf-11/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2011/07/01/debconf-11/</id>
    <published>2011-07-01T17:46:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft" style="margin: 20px;" title="No DebConf" src="http://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/images/no-debconf11.png" alt="" width="150" height="150">Last year, I had all the intention in the world to go to Bosnia and Herzegovina this summer to attend <a href="http://debconf11.debconf.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">DebConf 11</a>, but given my non-existent involvement on the project for the last couple of years, there’s no reason for me to do it. Even last year when the event was held in town, I was not entirely thrilled about it. Life has changed quite a bit in the last few years, allowing me to just find and allocate my priorities on their right places.</p>
<p>I hope everybody attending have a great time and snap lots of photos for me to see and regret not being there.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft" style="margin: 20px;" title="No DebConf" src="http://www.earth.li/~noodles/blog/images/no-debconf11.png" alt="" wi]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="debconf" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debconf/"/>
    
      <category term="debconf11" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debconf11/"/>
    
      <category term="debian" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debian/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Disable Nginx logging]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2011/03/24/disable-nginx-logging/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2011/03/24/disable-nginx-logging/</id>
    <published>2011-03-24T20:47:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is something that is specified clearly on the <a href="http://wiki.nginx.org/Modules#Nginx_core_modules" target="_blank" rel="external">Nginx manual</a>, but it’s nice to have it as a quick reference.</p>
<p>The <tt>access_log</tt> and <tt>error_log</tt> directives on Nginx are on separate modules (<a href="http://wiki.nginx.org/HttpLogModule" target="_blank" rel="external">HTTP Log</a> and <a href="http://wiki.nginx.org/CoreModule" target="_blank" rel="external">Core</a> modules respectively) and they don’t behave the same way when all you want is to disable all logging on your server (in our case, <a href="http://nabbr.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">we</a> serve a gazillion static files and perform a lot of reverse proxying and we’re not interested on tracking that). It’s a common misconception that you can set error_log to off, because that’s how you disable access_log (if you do that, the server will still log to the file <tt>$nginx_path/off</tt>). Instead, you have to set <tt>error_log</tt> to log to the always mighty black hole <tt>/dev/null</tt> using the highest level for logging (which triggers the fewest events), <tt>crit</tt>:</p>
<p>[code]http {<br>  server {</p>
<pre><code><span class="comment"># ...</span>
<span class="title">access_log</span> <span class="built_in">off</span>;
<span class="title">error_log</span> /dev/null <span class="built_in">crit</span>;
<span class="comment"># ...</span>
</code></pre><p>  }</p>
<h1 id="…">…</h1><p>}[/code]</p>
<p>If you’re the possessor of the blingest of bling-bling, you can disable all logging (not only for a server block), by putting <tt>error_log</tt> on the root of the configuration and <tt>access_log</tt> within your http block and make sure you don’t override that on any of the inner blocks. And you’re good to go.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>This is something that is specified clearly on the <a href="http://wiki.nginx.org/Modules#Nginx_core_modules" target="_blank" rel="extern]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="http" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/http/"/>
    
      <category term="nginx" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/nginx/"/>
    
      <category term="tips" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/tips/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[GitHub (and open source) on LinkedIn]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2011/03/08/github-and-open-source-on-linkedin/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2011/03/08/github-and-open-source-on-linkedin/</id>
    <published>2011-03-08T18:07:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a huge fan of <a href="http://www.linkedin.com" target="_blank" rel="external">LinkedIn</a>, I love it. Handled properly, it can allow you to establish great opportunities that eventually lead up to either work or paid gigs and we all know how good money is, right? I have spent time for the last couple of weeks making sure <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/damog" target="_blank" rel="external">my own LinkedIn profile</a> is complete, fully up-to-date and that I’m taking full advantage of all the features that the site has to offer, and even though I’m not actively looking for a job it’s always nice to get contacted by other developers or directors (heck, even recruiters) inviting you to consider other job opportunities. In my own personal space, it makes me more confident that I can still be of great value to other enterprises. It’s like feeling you could date again, if you wanted to.</p>
<p>Last night, <a href="http://blog.linkedin.com/2011/03/08/github-linkedin/" target="_blank" rel="external">they announced</a> that they had enabled <a href="http://www.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a> as an application on users profiles. This is great for developers. I think that LinkedIn still needs to implement ways for users to track their not-so-formal activities and this is kind of a big step, to some extent.</p>
<p><a href="http://damog.net/old/stereonaut/2011/03/Screen-shot-2011-03-08-at-12.04.44-PM.png" target="_blank" rel="external"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1242" title="Screen shot 2011-03-08 at 12.04.44 PM" src="http://damog.net/old/stereonaut/2011/03/Screen-shot-2011-03-08-at-12.04.44-PM-300x186.png" alt="" width="300" height="186"></a></p>
<p>For instance, I’d like to list some projects that I’ve worked with on which I wasn’t fully employed with but hired me as a contractor for a few hours. They need to implement some sort of portfolio for the side business you perform.</p>
<p>After all, a LinkedIn profile is based on the professional work you do, not entirely on the commits you do into a forked or your never-ending project. There’s still the question on how you can show off additional open source experience that is not in the form of commits on a GitHub repo, for instance, how to display the work you do on a project that doesn’t have a Git repository, and use something else; or maybe the translation work you’ve done for years; or the documentation you’ve contributed here and there. But then again, if you’re depending on LinkedIn to show off your open source expertise, you’re probably not using the right tool. While I applaud the GitHub integration on LinkedIn, I do think it still lacks more work to cover more open source contributions which can take up to significant amounts of time on a developers expertise skills set.</p>
<p>Go add the GitHub application to your LinkedIn profile <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/opensocialInstallation/preview?_ch_panel_id=1&amp;_applicationId=122233" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I am a huge fan of <a href="http://www.linkedin.com" target="_blank" rel="external">LinkedIn</a>, I love it. Handled properly, it can all]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="github" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/github/"/>
    
      <category term="linkedin" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/linkedin/"/>
    
      <category term="open source" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/open-source/"/>
    
      <category term="work" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/work/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[YouTube's HTML5 trial opt-in]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2011/03/02/youtube-html5-trial-opt/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2011/03/02/youtube-html5-trial-opt/</id>
    <published>2011-03-03T04:24:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you use any <em>non</em>-retarded Web browser (aka not Internet Explorer) and usually run into and enjoy the huge inventory of videos that <a href="http://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">YouTube</a> has to offer, please consider opting in to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/html5" target="_blank" rel="external">YouTube’s HTML5 trial</a>, which means that you’ll be running HTML5 browser-based video instead of <a href="http://flashsucks.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Flash</a> for most of the website’s videos. If you’re also nerd enough, make sure to send them <a href="http://www.google.com/support/forum/p/youtube/label" target="_blank" rel="external">feedback</a> and shit.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>If you use any <em>non</em>-retarded Web browser (aka not Internet Explorer) and usually run into and enjoy the huge inventory of videos ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="html5" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/html5/"/>
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/video/"/>
    
      <category term="youtube" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/youtube/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Twitter feed for Planet Perl Iron Man]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2011/02/02/twitter-feed-for-planet-perl-iron-man/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2011/02/02/twitter-feed-for-planet-perl-iron-man/</id>
    <published>2011-02-02T23:58:20.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like to read <a href="http://ironman.enlightenedperl.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Planet Perl Iron Man</a>, but since I’m less and less of a user of <a href="http://google.com/reader" target="_blank" rel="external">Google Reader</a> these days, I prefer to follow interesting feeds on <a href="http://twitter.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Twitter</a> instead: I don’t have to digest all of the content on my timeline, only when I’m in the mood to see what’s going on out there. So, if you wanna follow the account, find it as @<a href="http://twitter.com/perlironman" target="_blank">perlironman</a>. If interested, you can also follow <a href="http://twitter.com/_damog" target="_blank" rel="external">me</a>. That is all.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I like to read <a href="http://ironman.enlightenedperl.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Planet Perl Iron Man</a>, but since I’m less ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="twitter" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/twitter/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Running find with two or more commands to -exec]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2010/09/28/running-find-with-two-or-more-commands-to-exec/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2010/09/28/running-find-with-two-or-more-commands-to-exec/</id>
    <published>2010-09-28T17:02:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent a couple of minutes today trying to understand how to make <a href="http://unixhelp.ed.ac.uk/CGI/man-cgi?find" target="_blank"><tt>find (1)</tt></a> to execute two commands on the same target.</p>
<p>Instead of this or any similar crappy variants:</p>
<p><code lang="bash">$ find . -type d -iname “*0” -mtime +60 -exec scp -r -P 1337 “{}” “meh.server.com:/mnt/1/backup/storage” &amp;&amp; rm -rf “{}” \;</code></p>
<p>Try something like this:</p>
<p><code lang="bash">$ find . -type d -iname “*0” -mtime +60 -exec scp -r -P 1337 “{}” “meh.server.com:/mnt/1/backup/storage” \; -exec rm -rf “{}” \;</code></p>
<p>Which is:</p>
<p><code lang="bash">$ find . -exec command {} \; -exec other command {} \;</code></p>
<p>And you’re good to go.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I spent a couple of minutes today trying to understand how to make <a href="http://unixhelp.ed.ac.uk/CGI/man-cgi?find" target="_blank"><t]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="bash" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/bash/"/>
    
      <category term="find" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/find/"/>
    
      <category term="tips" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/tips/"/>
    
      <category term="unix" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/unix/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Perl 5.12's each function]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2010/09/23/perl-5-12s-each-function/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2010/09/23/perl-5-12s-each-function/</id>
    <published>2010-09-23T22:21:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With Perl <a href="http://www.nntp.perl.org/group/perl.perl5.porters/2010/04/msg158820.html" target="_blank" rel="external">5.12</a> released earlier this summer, the <a href="http://perldoc.perl.org/functions/each.html" target="_blank" rel="external">each</a> function got a nice little addition that I’d like to talk about: It now has the ability to work on arrays, not only key-value pair hashes, but not exactly as you’d expect it (not like Ruby’s <a href="http://ruby-doc.org/core/classes/Array.html#M002173" target="_blank" rel="external">each</a> method).</p>
<p>The traditional way to work with each, using a hash:</p>
<p><code lang="perl">my %h = (<br>a =&gt; 1,<br>b =&gt; 2,<br>c =&gt; 3,<br>);</code></p>
<p>while(my($key, $value) = each %h) {<br>say “index: $key =&gt; value: $value”;<br>}</p>
<p>And the output. Of course, hashes being unordered lists, you won’t get the nice little order of an array.</p>
<p>[text]index: c =&gt; value: 3<br>index: a =&gt; value: 1<br>index: b =&gt; value: 2<br>[/text]</p>
<p>Now, when you use an array, each will return the next pair on the list consisting on the index of that element’s position and the position itself. Since it returns the next pair, you can iterate through it on the same fashion as when using a hash:</p>
<p><code lang="perl">my @arr = (‘a’..’z’);</code></p>
<p>while(my($index, $value) = each @arr) {<br>say “index: $index =&gt; value: $value”;<br>}</p>
<p>This is particularly useful to access direct named variables, both the index and the element, while looping through an array.</p>
<p>[text]index: 0 =&gt; value: a<br>index: 1 =&gt; value: b<br>index: 2 =&gt; value: c<br>index: 3 =&gt; value: d<br>index: 4 =&gt; value: e<br>index: 5 =&gt; value: f<br>index: 6 =&gt; value: g<br>index: 7 =&gt; value: h<br>index: 8 =&gt; value: i<br>index: 9 =&gt; value: j<br>index: 10 =&gt; value: k<br>index: 11 =&gt; value: l<br>index: 12 =&gt; value: m<br>index: 13 =&gt; value: n<br>index: 14 =&gt; value: o<br>index: 15 =&gt; value: p<br>index: 16 =&gt; value: q<br>index: 17 =&gt; value: r<br>index: 18 =&gt; value: s<br>index: 19 =&gt; value: t<br>index: 20 =&gt; value: u<br>index: 21 =&gt; value: v<br>index: 22 =&gt; value: w<br>index: 23 =&gt; value: x<br>index: 24 =&gt; value: y<br>index: 25 =&gt; value: z</p>
<p>[/text]</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>With Perl <a href="http://www.nntp.perl.org/group/perl.perl5.porters/2010/04/msg158820.html" target="_blank" rel="external">5.12</a> rele]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="perl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl/"/>
    
      <category term="perl 5.12" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/perl-5-12/"/>
    
      <category term="tips" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/tips/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Apache2::Archive 0.2]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2010/08/22/apache2archive-0-2/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2010/08/22/apache2archive-0-2/</id>
    <published>2010-08-23T00:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://search.cpan.org/dist/Apache2-Archive" target="_blank" rel="external">Apache2::Archive</a> is a mod_perl 2 extension that allows the Apache HTTP server to expose tar and tar.gz archives on the fly. When a client requests such an archive file, the server will return a page displaying information about the file that allows the user to view or download individual files from within the archive.</p>
<p>I just uploaded version <strong>0.2</strong> to <a href="http://search.cpan.org/~damog" target="_blank" rel="external">CPAN</a> and <a href="http://github.com/damog/apache2-archive/tree/0.2" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a> correcting a few automatic build issues presented with dependencies. Grab it now with <tt><a href="http://search.cpan.org/dist/App-CPAN-Fresh/" target="_blank" rel="external">cpanf</a></tt>!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://search.cpan.org/dist/Apache2-Archive" target="_blank" rel="external">Apache2::Archive</a> is a mod_perl 2 extension that ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[curl POST data and newlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2010/08/15/curl-post-data-and-newlines/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2010/08/15/curl-post-data-and-newlines/</id>
    <published>2010-08-16T03:10:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m writing a <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Rails</a> application for the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microblogging" target="_blank" rel="external">microblogging</a> strategy for <a href="http://debian.org" target="_blank" rel="external">Debian</a> (which I used to call, <a href="http://github.com/damog/debian-twitter" target="_blank" rel="external">debian-twitter</a>, but you know how us Debian folks are :D). I came up with a strange issue, that at first I thought was <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/action_controller_overview.html" target="_blank" rel="external">ActionController</a>‘s fault or some crap.</p>
<p>So, I was testing one of my controllers with something like this:</p>
<p><code lang="bash">cat /tmp/mm.txt | curl -d @- <a href="http://localhost:3000/message/new" target="_blank" rel="external">http://localhost:3000/message/new</a></code></p>
<p>/tmp/mm.txt is a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pretty_Good_Privacy" target="_blank" rel="external">PGP</a> signed message which then I just send as POST data to my application. So far so good. However, when accessing the data from Rails, using request.body.read, I was a getting a single line, with the newlines (carriage returns) removed. So I started looking at how ActionController was getting the HTTP data and stuff. But then I tested:</p>
<p><code lang="bash">cat /tmp/mm.txt | lwp-request -m POST  <a href="http://localhost:3000/message/new" target="_blank" rel="external">http://localhost:3000/message/new</a></code></p>
<p>And that had the carriage returns in place.</p>
<p>So, I started looking at the curl man page and discovered this little gem:</p>
<p><blockquote>—data-binary &lt;data&gt;</blockquote></p>
<p>(HTTP) This posts data exactly as specified with no extra processing whatsoever.</p>
<p>If you start the data with the letter @, the rest should be a filename. Data is posted in a similar manner as —data-ascii does, except that newlines are preserved and conversions are never done.</p>
<p>If this option is used several times, the ones following the first will append data as described in -d/—data.<br><code lang="bash">cat /tmp/mm.txt | curl —data-binary @- <a href="http://localhost:3000/message/new" target="_blank" rel="external">http://localhost:3000/message/new</a></code></p>
<p>…did indeed the tricky. Maybe someone needs this info some day.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I’m writing a <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Rails</a> application for the <a href="http://en.wikipedia]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="code" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/code/"/>
    
      <category term="curl" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/curl/"/>
    
      <category term="debian" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debian/"/>
    
      <category term="rails" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/rails/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[DebConf 10]]></title>
    <link href="http://damog.net/blog/2010/08/12/debconf-10/"/>
    <id>http://damog.net/blog/2010/08/12/debconf-10/</id>
    <published>2010-08-12T07:04:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-05-18T17:17:44.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was in New York for three full weeks, before, during and after DebConf 10 took place. Unfortunately, I wasn’t able to attend talks or go hang out with folks as much as I would’ve wanted. Most of the time I was busy at the office with a new product launch we have been preparing for the last few months. However, I was able to come and say hi to a few people, attend the C&amp;W party and talk with friends and ran into. I was, however, following all conversations on IRC so I was pretty informed of all of what was going on. Some random thoughts:</p>
<p><ul><br>    <li>Being surrounded by so many amazing Debian people made me realize how much I’ve been apart from the project. My involvement decreased pretty much since I moved to New York. But because of that, I’m now slowly retaking my activity, trying to work on actual things that I use on my daily work instead of just packaging tons of shit that nobody really cared about.</li><br>    <li>DebConf is pretty awesome. After attending six out of the last seven Debian conferences, you get to establish a nice connection with people and they become your friends. This year, even if I only came a couple of nights, I made stronger friendships, and for that I’m thankful. It is only within Debian that this human part of bonding really takes place.</li><br>    <li>I really regret missing a couple of events: First, the Day trip to Coney Island and the Cyclones game; and the group photo. Both because of work, yes.</li><br>    <li>It was interesting to hear the thoughts from one of the Bosnian attendees about next year’s DebConf there. I’m really sorry I can’t recall his name, but it shocked a bit that he stated that they might try to find <em>better speakers</em> next year, because a lot of them “sucked a lot” here. All I can say is that, even though everybody’s opinions are valid, this might come from an outsider, not used to Debian conferences. Where are you going to find better speakers? Us developers are the only speakers out there, good or bad, we are the ones making the conferences by and for.</li><br>    <li>I like Zach’s attitude as DPL, even when I introduced him to a very nice friend of mine that came to the party to hang out.</li><br></ul><br>DebConf 10 rocked and I appreciate everybody’s participation in it. See you in Banja Luka, next year!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I was in New York for three full weeks, before, during and after DebConf 10 took place. Unfortunately, I wasn’t able to attend talks or g]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="debconf" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debconf/"/>
    
      <category term="debconf10" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debconf10/"/>
    
      <category term="debian" scheme="http://damog.net/blog/tags/debian/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>