<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gem on David Moreno blog</title>
    <link>https://damog.net/blog/tag/gem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gem on David Moreno blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 10:40:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://damog.net/blog/tag/gem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: On DebGem</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/01/08/re-on-debgem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 10:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/01/08/re-on-debgem/</guid>
      <description>Wouter, I find your thinking on DebGem a bit overreacted. I think you are taking the product and commercial efforts that a company make as the proposed solution we&amp;rsquo;ve all been expecting for a similar problem, which is not. You are considering DebGem to be an outcome provided by the Ruby community, which is not, to this issue.
Phusion is obviously not the Ruby community, but part of it. How I see it, it&amp;rsquo;s great: I applaud that more companies take a look at nice technologies and try to provide their own products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby goodies: Modules and methods for my everyday Ruby</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/01/03/ruby-goodies-modules-and-methods-for-my-everyday-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 23:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/01/03/ruby-goodies-modules-and-methods-for-my-everyday-ruby/</guid>
      <description>I make a lot of Web script processing, whether scraping, webservices, systems administration, etc. Because I sometimes happen to repeat small and useful chunks of code for different projects, I thought that, given making new modules and methods is usually hassleless in Ruby, I should make my own set of methods and goodies I constantly use. Example 1, I sometimes miss Perl&amp;rsquo;s LWP::Simple simplicity where I just pass a URL to a subroutine and get the content on a variable, quick, one-liner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>