<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on David Moreno blog</title>
    <link>https://damog.net/blog/tag/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on David Moreno blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 11:47:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://damog.net/blog/tag/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DebConf 10 restricted access</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2010/07/30/debconf-10-restricted-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 11:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2010/07/30/debconf-10-restricted-access/</guid>
      <description>This is how we roll at DebConf 10.
That chair protects our router :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Secure WordPress Plugins talk by Mark Jaquith</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/24/writing-secure-wordpress-plugins-talk-by-mark-jaquith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 17:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/24/writing-secure-wordpress-plugins-talk-by-mark-jaquith/</guid>
      <description>Continuing my notes and remarks from WordCamp, I attended Writing Secure Plugins, which was given by Mark Jaquith (@markjaquith on Twitter). I found the talk to be also slightly introductory on security matters but nicely oriented to WordPress plugins and general PHP Web app development. I believe most of the tips given should be taken into consideration by every PHP coder out there, not just WP people. 
The talk was split into the different attacks that are common on Web applications and mainly pointing to functions and actions to be taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing WordPress talk</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/20/securing-wordpress-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 13:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/20/securing-wordpress-talk/</guid>
      <description>Here I start a series of posts with my comments, notes and remarks on the talks that I attended at last weekend&amp;rsquo;s WordCamp in NYC.
The first talk I attended was Securing WordPress, by Brad Williams (@williamsba on Twitter). First off, this talk wasn&amp;rsquo;t too technical since it was focused to beginning developers whose background wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be completely into systems administration, it was intended to a broader audience, which is exactly why I liked it so much and started taking notes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>