<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on David Moreno blog</title>
    <link>https://damog.net/blog/tag/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on David Moreno blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 22:17:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://damog.net/blog/tag/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One year</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2013/08/06/one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 22:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2013/08/06/one-year/</guid>
      <description>A year ago today, I started working for Booking.com. I wish I could say that the time has flown by, but it really hasn&amp;rsquo;t. It has been one hell of a ride on all fronts: work, learning experiences, friends, but specially at home, since working for this company didn&amp;rsquo;t come without a complete life change. So far so good, and for that I&amp;rsquo;m grateful :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another day, another dawn</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2012/08/18/another-day-another-dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 14:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2012/08/18/another-day-another-dawn/</guid>
      <description>I started working for Booking.com two weeks ago now. These last two months have been probably the most chaotic and hectic in a long time from what I remember in my life. I left New York City, chilled out in Mexico City for several weeks and then finally relocated to beautiful Amsterdam. The decision of leaving New York was not simple, but I decided to take on new challenges, one cycle had ended for me and it was time for me to move on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a brogrammer, brah!</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2012/07/27/im-a-brogrammer-brah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 13:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2012/07/27/im-a-brogrammer-brah/</guid>
      <description>My professional career has been kind of an interesting one. I believe that when I diverted from being a completely stereotype of a geek, my career as an IT professional really took off. Or at least, the real experience: that experience that no words can describe on a resume but that only you have within, that experience that only comes up when you&amp;rsquo;re facing a real-life problem and no interviews or screening processes or algorithms challenges and tests can really discover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I quit</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2012/07/25/i-quit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 12:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2012/07/25/i-quit/</guid>
      <description>I just recently quit my job at the startup company I had been working in for almost five years. In startup terms, such long time might be a whole lifetime, but in my case, I grew liking it more and more as the years came, I had evolved from being just another engineer, to lead a team of seven great developers, with decision-making tasks and strategy planning for our technical infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned and real experience</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2012/03/05/lessons-learned-and-real-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 16:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2012/03/05/lessons-learned-and-real-experience/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been building a next generation video ad serving platform with all of lessons and experience we&amp;rsquo;ve gained over the last couple of years and specially over last one. In an industry where there&amp;rsquo;s too much client demand there&amp;rsquo;s only a few key supply players doing a good job and we&amp;rsquo;ve identified strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats. We&amp;rsquo;ve kept ourselves busy.
Over the course of last year, especially on the second half and as far as this first quarter of 2012 has been running, aims for a new better product have made me reconsider what I thought I knew and what I thought I had to learn on an engineering point of view, about how to build not only regular or good software, but enterprise software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub (and open source) on LinkedIn</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2011/03/08/github-and-open-source-on-linkedin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 12:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2011/03/08/github-and-open-source-on-linkedin/</guid>
      <description>I am a huge fan of LinkedIn, I love it. Handled properly, it can allow you to establish great opportunities that eventually lead up to either work or paid gigs and we all know how good money is, right? I have spent time for the last couple of weeks making sure my own LinkedIn profile is complete, fully up-to-date and that I&amp;rsquo;m taking full advantage of all the features that the site has to offer, and even though I&amp;rsquo;m not actively looking for a job it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to get contacted by other developers or directors (heck, even recruiters) inviting you to consider other job opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solicito desarrollador Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2010/08/09/solicito-desarrollador-ruby-on-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 09:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2010/08/09/solicito-desarrollador-ruby-on-rails/</guid>
      <description>Estoy en busca de un desarrollador Ruby y Ruby on Rails para unirse a la empresa en la cual estoy trabajando en Nueva York. La posición es para trabajar permanentemente desde la Ciudad de México en la Col. Roma con muy buenas facilidades, ambiente y un salario altamente competitivo.
A continuación la descripción de la oferta:
Selectable Media is looking for a talented engineer to be a major contributor to the development of its new social video platform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>