<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter on David Moreno blog</title>
    <link>https://damog.net/blog/tag/twitter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twitter on David Moreno blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 17:58:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://damog.net/blog/tag/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter feed for Planet Perl Iron Man</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2011/02/02/twitter-feed-for-planet-perl-iron-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 17:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2011/02/02/twitter-feed-for-planet-perl-iron-man/</guid>
      <description>I like to read Planet Perl Iron Man, but since I&amp;rsquo;m less and less of a user of Google Reader these days, I prefer to follow interesting feeds on Twitter instead: I don&amp;rsquo;t have to digest all of the content on my timeline, only when I&amp;rsquo;m in the mood to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on out there. So, if you wanna follow the account, find it as @perlironman. If interested, you can also follow me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2010</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2010/01/02/2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 00:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2010/01/02/2010/</guid>
      <description>My blog has served me throughout the years as a getaway medium. I&amp;rsquo;ve found comfort writing its pages, and more recently, writing a little bit more of my technical life and whereabouts. The personal side of it, in spite of being very well handled in the past, has been left behind in recent times. And I believe Twitter has taken that part of my postings. However, I believe that a lot of the thing I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing in my life are based on the measurable fact of the impact or weight that those actions would have on my Twitter (and Facebook for that matter) stream and contacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌✌</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/08/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2009 12:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/08/09/</guid>
      <description>Yes, those are twenty-five hands. As of yesterday 8&amp;frasl;8, I turned 25. Thanks to all of you who shouted out on Facebook, Twitter or elsewhere.
Oh, the ephemeralness of time; adulthood, a low-hanging fruit now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally at DebConf 9</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/07/22/finally-at-debconf-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/07/22/finally-at-debconf-9/</guid>
      <description>After a random series of hazardous events, I&amp;rsquo;m finally at DebConf 9 in Cáceres, Spain. I&amp;rsquo;ll post more updates later, right now I&amp;rsquo;m trying to put my sh*t together and find my way through around here for the next couple of weeks. Interested people can always follow my microblogging feed too.
Love, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync your Twitter followers and friends</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/06/10/sync-your-twitter-followers-and-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/06/10/sync-your-twitter-followers-and-friends/</guid>
      <description>I have a couple of accounts in Twitter (namely @debian and @planetalinux) that are starting to bring a lot of followers (well, at least some of them). And given that I consider these accounts to be Twitter-polite enough, I like to follow the followers back too; however, this task sometimes gets really hard and it&amp;rsquo;s tiring to go through the followers pages and follow those that I don&amp;rsquo;t follow yet over and over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheating the world you tweet less</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/06/08/cheating-the-world-you-tweet-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 16:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/06/08/cheating-the-world-you-tweet-less/</guid>
      <description>The number of updates on my Twitter page kind of bothers me sometimes. It&amp;rsquo;s a reminder of the amount of time I&amp;rsquo;ve spent and wasted on Twitter, it&amp;rsquo;s an ever-itching mole in front of my face. However, I can cheat the system and society and still feel good about myself. What if I just remove all freaking replies I&amp;rsquo;ve made, except for those of people I do care about (like my fiance or Ruby Boobie)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@debianproject is now @debian!</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/06/05/debianproject-is-now-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 11:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/06/05/debianproject-is-now-debian/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Jamie, who used to have the name registered and now handed it over, Twitter Debian&amp;rsquo;s Twitter username is now @debian (go follow Jamie now!). If you were already following @debianproject, nothing will change.
Having @debian on Twitter is actually kind of awesome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Maintainers now able to post to Debian Twitter</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/05/26/debian-maintainers-now-able-to-post-to-debian-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 15:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/05/26/debian-maintainers-now-able-to-post-to-debian-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added support for Debian Maintainers to post tweets to Debian Twitter (both on Identi.ca and Twitter). Feel free to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter&#39;s OAuth &#43; Perl</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/05/21/twitters-oauth-perl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 14:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/05/21/twitters-oauth-perl/</guid>
      <description>During the last week, unbeatable Tatsuhiko Miyagawa uploaded Net::Twitter::OAuth to CPAN, which provides an awesome interface for Net::OAuth::Simple and Twitter by subclassing Net::Twitter. This way, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to develop Twitter client applications using its new OAuth method dropping the need for users to hand their credentials to third parties.
You will have to register your application on Twitter previously. You can do so here. If this is a web application that you will be building, you can provide a callback URL which is the page where the user will get redirected once she has granted access to your application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perl in the Time of Social Networks</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/05/09/perl-in-the-time-of-social-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 12:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/05/09/perl-in-the-time-of-social-networks/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a fantastic and exciting Perl summer.
During the last week, I received notification that the talk I&amp;rsquo;ve proposed for both YAPC::NA and YAPC::EU, was accepted.
I will be talking about Perl in the Time of Social Networks, which is mainly two broad things: how Perl can actively power a modern social networking site (I&amp;rsquo;ll be releasing a free -as in speech- social network website, similar to Lovd or RailSpace, built with pure Catalyst); and about high-load applications dealing with social networks&amp;rsquo; APIs and users (a Moose-based universal social network distributor), with Twitter, Facebook, MySpace, Blogger, LastFM, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Twitter alerts and regular expressions</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/04/12/on-twitter-alerts-and-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2009 07:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/04/12/on-twitter-alerts-and-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;m the only one that does something like this, but I certainly trust I&amp;rsquo;m not alone.
I love regular expressions (to which some people say there&amp;rsquo;s nothing regular about) and I just found TweetBeep recently, which is a simple alerts system. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing really new or innovative about it, given that you can get the results yourself using advanced search on Twitter and consuming the results from a feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rubx: Twitter&#39;s Ruby shell</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/04/06/rubx-twitters-ruby-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 09:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/04/06/rubx-twitters-ruby-shell/</guid>
      <description>Rubx, also known as Ruby Boobie, is a nice spoiled girlie bot that runs on Twitter. She listens when you talk to her and when you do, it&amp;rsquo;ll better be with Ruby: She will interpret your tweet in Ruby and reply to you with what your code returns.
How does it work? You send a message to her: @rubx &amp;ldquo;The day I was born it was a &amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;&amp;lt; Time.local(1984, &amp;ldquo;aug&amp;rdquo;, 8).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/03/22/debian-on-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 09:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/03/22/debian-on-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Or&amp;hellip; for those who care about Twitter and Debian :)
We&amp;rsquo;ve setup a Twitter account for the project to use on Twitter. Go follow it, go now! twitter.com/debianproject
Now, the interesting part about this is that any Debian developer with a GPG key on the Debian keyring can tweet to it. You basically only have to do something like this:
$ echo &amp;quot;Squeeze is scheduled for Winter 2014&amp;quot; | gpg --clearsign | lwp-request -m POST http://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s first tweet</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/02/26/googles-first-tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/02/26/googles-first-tweet/</guid>
      <description>Google created an official Twitter account. Its first tweet was something odd:
 I&amp;rsquo;m 01100110 01100101 01100101 01101100 01101001 01101110 01100111 00100000 01101100 01110101 01100011 01101011 01111001 00001010
 I had previously written (in Spanish, for La Columna de Perl), how to quickly decode this &amp;ldquo;way&amp;rdquo; of binary writing with Perl&amp;rsquo;s chr and oct. So, to find out what was Google really tweeting, run:
perl -e &#39;map { print chr oct &amp;quot;0b&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TwitVim: Nice Twitter client</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/01/10/twitvim-nice-twitter-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 17:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/01/10/twitvim-nice-twitter-client/</guid>
      <description>I do like Twitter. For quite some time now I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find a Twitter client that I&amp;rsquo;d really like. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, lots of them, Twhirl, Twitux, microblog-purple (which I started to dislike since I&amp;rsquo;m not IMing that much anymore and it can become extremely annoying if not blocked), TweetDeck, etc. All of them don&amp;rsquo;t seem to fill my own needs and preferences. Even when Twitter used to support IM, I came up with probably the best solution I&amp;rsquo;ve used so far, GTalk on Bitlbee, so I could easily use Irssi with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebbie @ Twitter</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2008/10/12/ebbie-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 13:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2008/10/12/ebbie-twitter/</guid>
      <description>En enero pasado, Raquel y yo adoptamos a una linda criatura peluda, con garras, colmillos y bigotes. Ebbie es nuestra pequeña hija felina. Como ella no es mexicana, si no neoyorkina, no habla muy bien español, pero ronronea y gruñe en inglés gatuno del ghetto. 
Recientemente Ebbie registró su cuenta de Twitter que actualiza cada que se le pega la gana para que el mundo sepa sobre sus andanzas, acicalamiento y bolas de pelos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter de Planeta Linux</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2008/09/11/twitter-de-planeta-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 12:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2008/09/11/twitter-de-planeta-linux/</guid>
      <description>Pues algunos de los que me siguen ya lo habrán visto: hemos colocado una cuenta de Twitter en donde se sindican los feeds de todas las instancias de Planeta Linux. Es una buena forma para seguirle la pista a los alrededor de 550 blogs que Planeta Linux abarca en sus doce instancias.
http://twitter.com/planetalinux
¡Disfrútenlo!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>