<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordpress on David Moreno blog</title>
    <link>https://damog.net/blog/tag/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wordpress on David Moreno blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 11:35:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://damog.net/blog/tag/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Large PHP scripts truncated on nginx</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2010/02/03/large-php-scripts-truncated-on-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 11:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2010/02/03/large-php-scripts-truncated-on-nginx/</guid>
      <description>I spent a couple of hours yesterday trying to debug an issue that made me hit my head against the wall while it lasted.
I run multiple instances of WordPress, and with it, comes a nice little editor bundled called TinyMCE. But on my main WordPress installation (this very blog, dear reader, where you are reading this from), TinyMCE wouldn&amp;rsquo;t come up, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t render properly on the browser, it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter if it was my main browser, Chrome, or Firefox, Safari, cached, uncached, it was just broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caching and optimization for WordPress talk</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/12/21/caching-and-optimization-for-wordpress-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 14:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/12/21/caching-and-optimization-for-wordpress-talk/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with my WordCamp NYC talks review, I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out the notes I took attending the talk Caching and Optimization for WordPress, by Jeremy Clarke.
I believe this was a great topic to be covered for people who actively maintain WordPress installations and have to deal with upgrades, stability and reliability. However, I also think Jeremy took a much more basic approach for this topic the way it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Secure WordPress Plugins talk by Mark Jaquith</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/24/writing-secure-wordpress-plugins-talk-by-mark-jaquith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 17:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/24/writing-secure-wordpress-plugins-talk-by-mark-jaquith/</guid>
      <description>Continuing my notes and remarks from WordCamp, I attended Writing Secure Plugins, which was given by Mark Jaquith (@markjaquith on Twitter). I found the talk to be also slightly introductory on security matters but nicely oriented to WordPress plugins and general PHP Web app development. I believe most of the tips given should be taken into consideration by every PHP coder out there, not just WP people. 
The talk was split into the different attacks that are common on Web applications and mainly pointing to functions and actions to be taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing WordPress talk</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/20/securing-wordpress-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 13:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/20/securing-wordpress-talk/</guid>
      <description>Here I start a series of posts with my comments, notes and remarks on the talks that I attended at last weekend&amp;rsquo;s WordCamp in NYC.
The first talk I attended was Securing WordPress, by Brad Williams (@williamsba on Twitter). First off, this talk wasn&amp;rsquo;t too technical since it was focused to beginning developers whose background wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be completely into systems administration, it was intended to a broader audience, which is exactly why I liked it so much and started taking notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wonderful WordCamp NYC experience</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/15/wonderful-wordcamp-nyc-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 20:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/15/wonderful-wordcamp-nyc-experience/</guid>
      <description>I had a blast on Saturday. Let me put it again in bold, I had an awesome experience yesterday at WordCamp NYC. If you ever have the opportunity, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t miss the chance to attend one of them, it&amp;rsquo;s really inspiring, people is very, very welcome and I loved the fact that there&amp;rsquo;s so many people with all sorts of backgrounds and focused on many fronts on the Web and blogging world, not just technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending WordCamp NYC</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/10/attending-wordcamp-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 17:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2009/11/10/attending-wordcamp-nyc/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be attending WordCamp NYC this upcoming weekend. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of very interesting talks and people speaking at the conference, so it was basically a no-brainer since it&amp;rsquo;s being held in Manhattan. Plus, WordPress is one of the platforms I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked and admired on how they have achieved to become a mainstream product with a huge amount of active users and developers. I started using it way back in 2004 when it was b2/cafelog, so it&amp;rsquo;s been a long ride.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>