<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amor on David Moreno blog</title>
    <link>https://damog.net/blog/tag/amor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amor on David Moreno blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:22:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://damog.net/blog/tag/amor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gracias 2</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2008/11/27/gracias-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 21:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2008/11/27/gracias-2/</guid>
      <description>Aunque en realidad la gente no da gracias y es un hecho meramente histórico, la celebración de thanksgivin&amp;rsquo; me hace reflexionar al respecto de a quién y por qué daría gracias.
Dicho lo anterior.
Le doy gracias a Dios por hacerme feliz. Por tener la mejor mujer del mundo, la mejor familia, los mejores amigos y una vida llena de sueños, anhelos y esperanzas. Le doy gracias a Dios por colmarme de amor, por bendecirme con una vida tan plena y completa como la que creo tener.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 24th, 1958</title>
      <link>https://damog.net/blog/2008/07/24/july-24th-1958/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 09:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damog.net/blog/2008/07/24/july-24th-1958/</guid>
      <description>Today, fifty years ago, my mother was born.
On July 24th, 1958, Vicenta Leyva gave birth to Olga Cristina Garza Leyva in the small town of Zumpango del Río (later renamed to Eduardo Neri), in the southern Mexican state of Guerrero. Her father Guillermo Garza, who is still alive, was a private pilot. Olga Cristina was named Cristina after the saint that is celebrated on the same day.
She was their third kid, a couple of years before Víctor and Guillermo were born and a couple of years after, Carlos was born, all of them being born on total different places on southern and central Mexico.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>